CHlNA, DURING THE SlNO-JAPANESE WAR
A BITTER POWER STRUGGLE TEARS THE COUNTRY APART
VICE PRESIDENT WANG DECLARES A NEW GOVERNMENT
BACKED BY THE INVADING JAPANESE ARMY
THIS PUPPET REGIME TRIES TO LURE AWAY OFFICIALS
FROM CHIANG KAI-SHEK'S CAMP TO FURTHER GAIN FAVOR WITH HIS JAPANESE MASTERS
WANG BRUTALLY CLAMPS DOWN THE RESISTANCE
THAT SEEKS TO RETURN CHINA TO THE CHINESE
AS THE PUPPET REGIME GROWS MORE TYRANNICAL
THE RESISTANCE COUNTERS WITH INCREASINGLY BLOODY ASSASSINATIONS
< The Message >
cym合并中英字
OCTOBER 10, 1942...THE NATIONAL HOLIDAY
Sorry
对不起
We're closed tonight
今天这里不营业
How come? We're trying to celebrate
为什么今天过节啊
The whole restaurant's booked
场子被我们包了
Got it?
明白吗
Even General Tang has joined us
连唐生明将军都到南京跟汪主席合作了
And he's not the only one, of course You know General He and the rest of them
还有齐燮元，何行健，李长齐
We're beating back Chiang Kai-shek and his men in every battle
目前重庆方面是节节败退
His government won't be able to hold out much longer
蒋介石四面投降是迟早的事
President Wang holds you in the highest esteem
汪主席非常敬仰您
He sent me here to invite you
特别交代下来
to join him on the viewing platform at the ceremony
要我今天一定请您老到观礼台就坐
He would be most honored
even if you're only there briefly
哪怕就一分钟
President Wang needs the support of people like you
您的出面具有非常意义,和平政府需要像您这样的大家出来执掌局面
Go ahead
去吧
The Chungking-style chicken here is the genuine article
这里的粉蒸鸡可是纯正的重庆味儿
You've been holed up in the North too long. Have a taste
您隐居在北方 难得一尝
Mr. Fan
范老先生
I need your answer now
您好歹给我一个交代
"Wang's Intelligence Gunned Down by Rebels"
"Imperial Officer Poisoned"
"Terrorists Strike Down Imperial Officer"
"Rebels attack the Imperial Research Center"
"Transport Facility Destroyed in Rebel Bomb Attack"
"Japanese Imperial Officer Axed"
JAPANESE MILITARY POLICE DEPARTMENT -
Smells nice...
真香啊
Doesn't it?
这是一种香料
It comes from Sri Lanka
从斯里兰卡来的
Drives our Puppy crazy
八妞最喜欢
Now tell me - because you will sooner or later-
说吧 早晚都得说
Who do you get your orders from?
你们的情报是从哪来的
Puppy
八妞
Go
上
Colonel Takeda
武田长
You must be Mr. Six
您一定就是六爷
I'm a great admirer of your work
久仰
You're too kind
不敢不敢不敢
Col. Takeda has a remarkable command of Chinese
太君的中国话说的真是太好啦
She's a tough one
那女的很硬
We've tried everything at our disposal
用尽了一切手段
She won't break
都不肯开口
Then Mr. Six is the man for the job
那请六爷就对了
Don't let me keep you
一切拜托了
Just turn these assassinations over...
摧毁暗杀组织的事情
...to the Chinese authorities
交给汪政府的剿匪司令部就行了
You'll be sent back to the Home Islands soon enough
你马上就要被遣送回本土了
Don't get mixed up in all this
还搀和这做什么
Gen. Tsukeda, sir-
报告挂尾中将
The head of the Resistance...
这一系列暗杀行动
...is a man code-named Magnum
是反日组织领导人“老枪”策划的
Though he's never exposed himself
“老枪”一直神出鬼没
He is behind these assassinations
从未泄露过真面目
I've got a strong feeling that
我有强烈直觉
Magnum has a mole in our operations
我们的内部有老枪的卧底
Feelings are for women, Takeda
直觉是女人的擅长
Feelings don't have any place in war
武田君什么时候也开始靠直觉打仗了
My part in the war is almost over, sir
我即将退出战场
This would be my last chance to redeem myself
这是我的最后一次机会
I cannot return home as a failure. It would bring shame to my family
我不能饮败而归 致家族蒙羞
That woman finally cracked
那女的招了
She's with Magnum alright
她的确是老枪的部下
She says they get their orders
他们每次行动之前
from a message board in front of the city temple
都会有人在城隍庙前的告示栏，分别给他们贴发指令
The orders are written on a lottery flyer
指令都写在彩票广告上
That sounds like their M. O.
这符合他们的一贯做法
We found this in her home
这是从她家搜出来的
Has she ever met the person who posts the flyers?
她遇见过贴指令的人吗
She bumped into him once
撞见过一次
He's an old cripple
是个瘸子
CITY TEMPLE -
Commissioner, I've seen the cripple before
处长 我认识那个瘸子
He's a janitor at the Counterinsurgency Center.
他是我们司令部的清洁工
-Retreat! -Yes sir!
-撤        -是
Mission abort!
行动取消
You did the right thing
你放他走是对的
If you'd taken him in
要当场逮人
We'd have lost our only lead
线索就永远断了
If the person who posts the flyers is a janitor at our Counterinsurgency Center.
贴告示的那个人既然是我们司令部的清洁工
Then we can also presume
可以合理判断
that he's getting his information
给他情报的人
from someone else working at the Counterinsurgency Center.
也潜伏在司令部里
Correct
不错
Our sources say their codename is Phantom
线报显示这个卧底代号叫老鬼
The next move is ours
我来下个套吧
The recent surge in planned terrorist acts
Suggests a problem with our intelligence channels
General Osamu Tsukeda, The Imperial Army
invites Commander Zhang of Counterinsurgency Center and personnels involved
To meet at Bai Cao Hall...
On October 31, 9 p.m.
We shall discuss ongoing intelligence efforts
COUNTERINSURGENCY CENTER -
Li Ningyu, Head Officer of the Decoding Section
Gu Xiaomeng, Administration Officer of the Decoding Section
Wu Zhiguo, Chief Captain of Counterinsurgence
Jin Shenghuo, Section Chief of the Military Office
Bai Xiaonian, Aide to the Commander of Counterinsurgency For the Commander
独守空房呢
CITY TEMPLE, TWO DAYS LATER -
Tsukeda et al to gather at Bai Cao Hall on October 31
Request assassination plan from Magnum
Wait
噢 请等一下      好 好
We have to go
走
-Now? -Yes
-现在啊       -走
Where the hell are we?
这他妈什么地方啊
Spooky...
一塌糊涂
It used to be called Qiu Manor.
裘盛怀的别业
The Japanese have taken it over now...
这里被日本人收啦
Turned it into their own little pleasure palace
改成行宫
High-ranking officers only
只接待高级军官
Looks like this is serious matter
看来今晚这会议非同小可啊
And someone's......going to be in for it
说不定会要了谁的命
What makes you say that?
为什么
Didn't you see? The Chief of Special Services is here too
看不见特务处王处长来了吗
Chief Wang
老王
Good evening, everyone
大家好
May I suggest that you go to your rooms and freshen up first?
各位先回房休息
We'll meet in the conference room in half an hour
半小时以后会议室见
What do you mean, freshen up?
回什么房啊
Let's just get the meeting over with So that we can all go home
开完会就回去 什么都没带
Patience, Ms. Gu
顾小姐稍安勿躁
Just go to your room first
先回房
If you would
请
All right
走
Lieutenant Bai-
白长官
That room
那边
Chief Jin-
金处长
This way
这边
Chief Captain Wu-
吴大队
That way
这边
Where's ours?
哪个我们的呀
I'm still feeling sick
我还想吐
Fairy shed light on heaven's secrets Win every time with White Dove lottery tickets
鬼谷子泄天机，白鸽票必胜诀
3-6-4-4-5-6-0-2...
叁陆肆肆伍陆零两
What is this all about?
什么乱七八糟的
Total gibberish
不懂
The Imperial Army
这是今天下午
intercepted this coded message this afternoon
皇军拦截到的一份密码
At first glance, nothing more than an ad for the lottery
乍看是彩票广告
But according to our intelligence
但实际上
It contains a message from an underground organization
是地下恐怖组织在传递消息
Regarding a new wave of assassinations
跟他们新一波的暗杀活动有关
We've asked all of you here to
请诸位来
Help us crack the code
就是要破解这份密电
Before it's too late
防患于未然
You must be joking
滑稽了 在场除了李组长
None of us here are cryptographers except for Officer Li
都不是专业译电人员
What did you bring us here for?To play mahjongg?
来干吗
凑牌局呢
Officer Bai, this order came directly from the upper levels of the Japanese Army
白副官，命令由日本驻屯军军部直接下达
It would be best if everyone cooperated fully
还希望各位都能够全力配合
Does Commander Zhang know about this?
这件事情咱们军部知道吗
No
不知道
The commander is in Nanking on business
司令去南京出差了
Until the day after tomorrow
后天才回
All these numbers...
这都是数字啊
Don't look at me
别看我
I don't know anything about codes
电码我不懂
What about you?
您说呢
Not in my area of interest
我对这事儿不感兴趣
I specialize more in blackjack, mahjongg...
要说二八杠 推牌九
...that kind of thing
那我是专家
Li?
小李
Li
You're the expert here
这你的专业啊
What do you say?
你意见呢
It's no good.
没用
We can't crack it
解不出来的
These numbers
这一看
Have obviously been encrypted
就是加了密的电码
There are 18 characters in total
全长一共十八个字
To decode what they're meant to be. We'd need the codebook
要想破译 就得找出母本
Otherwise... We could be here for days and still come up with nothing
否则 就是坐在这想死了 也想不出来
Did you hear that?
听见了吗
Go tell the Japanese
跟日本人说去
We can't help them
这么弄怎么可能有结果
I want to go home
我要回家
I don't have time for this nonsense.
后天老子要去清乡剿匪
I've got a sweep to go out on tomorrow
没空跟这耗着
Col. Takeda...
武田长
Who's that?
谁啊
The head of intelligence for the Imperial Army
皇军特务机关长
It's a pleasure to meet you
久仰
A consummate professional, indeed
不愧是专业
Here's the codebook
这是母本
Shall we begin?
可以开始了吧
7-8-7-
拐捌拐幺
Got them.
刚写完
Jin?
老金
En
嗯
What are they doing there?
她们那忙什么呢
They're, um... uh...
Enough with the um-ing. What is it?
-她们那个就是 嗨        -别哼啊嗨的 说啊你
You've heard of Morse Code?
听说过摩斯电码吗
Get on with it
啰嗦
Now... Morse Code is used for telegrams all over the world
摩斯码啊 是一种国际通用的电码
With Chinese, it works a bit differently
用到咱们中文上面就是
Each Chinese character is represented by four digits
每四个数字代表一个汉字
There are seventy-two digits in this telegram
您比如说这封密电
Total of eighteen characters
原来的电码顺序
But the sender deliberately scrambled the digits before they sent it out
已经被这个发文者彻底地给弄乱了
Now Li over there is trying to figure out the algorithm they used.
小李呢
就是试图找出这个规律
Once she's got that She can decode the message
才能译出这电码的原意
One - Zero
幺洞
And?
什么幺洞
This can't be...
怎么会
What's wrong?
怎么了
Tsukeda et al to gather at Bai Cao Hall on October 31 Request assassination plan from Magnum
十月三十一日挂尾等齐聚百草堂  请同志袭杀之
What does it say
怎么样
They're planning to assassinate General Tsukeda
有人打算刺杀挂尾中将
We set a trap - a telegram with false summons to a meeting with Tsukeda
我们发出了一份假集会通知
The mole in our office took the bait
司令部里的内鬼信以为真
And sent this to their co-conspirators
就发出了行动的情报
You five are the only ones
百草堂的集会通知
Who had any contact with the original message
只有你们五个人经手
Which is to say-
也就是说
One of you is the mole
潜伏在司令部
Who's been leaking intelligence
窃取情报的老鬼
Under the name Phantom
就在你们之中
Whichever one of you it is
不管是谁
Just confess
请自首吧
I promise you'll be treated humanely
我保证你会受人道待遇
You'll forgive me
对不起
But I have my orders
职责所在
Nobody leaves the building
鬼不显身
Until the Phantom is found
没有人能走出这栋楼
Who are you writing to?
写信给谁呢
You scared me
鬼丫头
Dear sister... What are you writing a letter for
哎呀 写信有什么用啊
We'll be out of here in two days
等过两天我们出去了
I'll go find Liu myself
我就亲自去找刘先生
And give him a piece of my mind
好好惩治他
You really think we'll be out of here in two days
你还真以为过两天能出去
Sure- It's not hard to guess who this Phantom is...
对啊 想也知道谁是鬼啊
Tea?
给
You've got a split seam!
衣服开线了
On the left
左边
I'll stitch it up for you
我来帮你补
Take it off for me.
你脱下来
Wow, that's a big one
这么大的口子
Is there a sewing kit here?
有针线吗
I think so...
应该有吧
Bingo!
有
Found it!
还真有
Here, let me help
我帮你
There you go
好了
You once told me that your mother wanted you to be a proper lady, right?
你不是跟我说  你妈一直要把你培养成个大家闺秀吗
Yeah
对啊
This is the first time I've ever seen you doing anything ladylike
这还是第一次看你做女红啊
Sis...
玉姐
I don't know why
不知道为什么
But I've always felt close to you
我就是看你特别亲
Especially today...
特别是今天
What's wrong?
怎么了
Liu hasn't been by in days
刘林宗已经好几天不见了
Unfettered in the wild wastes
我本是卧龙岗上散淡的人
I mastered yin and yang, and knew the heavens...
论阴阳如反掌保定乾坤
What are you singing?
刚刚唱的什么调啊
The Empty City， It's an old Tangshan ballad, from Leting
唐山皮影戏--空城计
Sing some more
再来一段
Well-
那得
Would I be rewarded with a smoke?
赏支红圈抽
Here
接着
But when the country needed me, I fought...
先帝爷下南阳御驾三请
To cast out the pretender to the throne...
联东吴灭曹魏
Why, Captain Wu - I never knew you were from Leting
原来吴大队长也是唐山乐亭人
What-
咋的
You too
你也是
My grandfather always used to sing that when I was little
小时候常听我三爷爷唱这个来着
No kidding? What a coincidence
这可真是太巧了
With all the the people in the headquarters
司令部忒大，单位多人也多
We hardly ever get the chance to talk
也没什么机会聊天
I never thought I'd meet someone from my old hometown here
没想到在这儿认个老乡
It must be fate
缘分还真奇怪
There are plenty of people from around there in the headquarters
司令部唐山人很多啊
But not necessarily from Leting village
乐亭的不多
It might just be us
好像就我们两个人
Yeah
对
Say, after we get out of here in a couple days I'll take everyone out to celebrate. My treat
过两天出去了，我请大家喝大酒
Has Li made a move yet
李宁玉那边有什么动静
Still mooning over
还恋着那个话剧演员吧
Her actor boyfriend, Liu
心神不定的
Gu just said
顾晓梦说
She knows who the Phantom is
她知道谁是鬼
She seems a bit off
她有点洒吧
A bit spoiled, you mean
是有点娇气
She comes from money
家里背景硬
As for Officer Bai...
还有白副官
He's got friends in high places too
也是仗着有靠山
So I've heard his relationship with Commander Zhang...
之前就听说白小年和张司令
...is indeed very unique
关系匪浅
I SLIPPED UP
MEETING AT BAI CAO HALL IS A TRAP
MUST GET MESSAGE OUT IN NEXT FIVE DAYS
OR COMRADES WILL GO TO THEIR DEATHS
Come, Bai
来了 小白
We're all waiting on you
等你呢
Here, have something to eat
看看吃点什么
Quite a spread.
这么丰盛
Is this supposed to be our last supper
吃的上路饭吗
My old friend Bai, always the joker...
你呀 就爱说笑
That pretty little head of yours
老唱青衣可惜了
Is just full of jokes
可以试试花旦
You can count me out
我整不了这个
I'm no spy-
我哪干得了间谍
I faint at the sight of chicken blood You think I'd join the resistance?
我连杀鸡都不敢，我有胆子当共产党
Wang-
老王
You know me
你知道我
This section chief position of mine...
我这个军机处长
It's bullshit, I got it through connections
说穿了就是个屁 裙带关系
You'd know better
是吧
My wife's related to Commander Zhang's wife on her father's side
我们家里的跟司令夫人那不是堂姐妹嘛
See?
哎
This all has to be a mistake
会不会是搞错了
I've never heard anything about any Phantom
从来没听说过什么老鬼
I mean
哎
Maybe it's the Japanese that have the mole...Right?
搞不好是他们日本人被渗透了 对吧
It couldn't be any more obvious
再明白不过了
Section Chief Jin is the one you want
你就朝金生火下手
He's the most suspicious of any of us
肯定能问出点蹊跷
Why?
凭什么这么说
He has a nephew
他有个侄子
Who joined the Red Army when he was only 15
十五岁就投了共军
He's become chief of staff at their headquarters in Yenan
听说在延安干参谋长了都
Fence-sitter that he is Jin must still be in contact with him
像老金这种骑墙派 肯定暗中有联系
He's been keeping a mistress for years
他其实早就包养了小妾
With money from weapons smuggling
用的是走私军火的黑钱
Do I look like I'm joking now?
我像开玩笑吗
I've got dirt on everybody here, Including yours
我那儿谁的黑底都有 包括你的
What a rough job you have-
大哥真辛苦啊
Here all on your own
一个人啊
The others are downstairs for backup
这不都下楼支援去了吗
Backup?
支援
As if we were dangerous
跟真的一样啊
I need to make a phone call- just a short one
我想打个电话 就说两句
No can do
这事不行
It's just to call home, It won't be long, I promise
就打回家 就说两句 最多三句
You can even listen, if you want
要不你挨着我听啊
I told you, it's not an option
我不是跟你说了吗 不行就是不行
Fine, then I won't trouble you
算了 不为难你了
Here's the number to my house
这是我家的电话
And a list of the things I need
我就需要点东西
Can you call them for me and have them bring my things here?
要不你打给他们 让他们给我送过来
Pretty please?
求你了
Ms. Gu...
顾小姐
We need you to come with us
有请顾小姐
I don't know - I mean,
不知道
I'm not sure-
不清楚
Can't be certain...What do you want me to do?
没法确定，那你让我说什么
Make something up?
害人啊
No, no
不不不
Certainly not-
绝不能害人
You were the one who delivered the telegraph
电文是你经手的
Just try and think back
再仔细想想
Did you notice anything suspicious
看哪个环节上不对劲
It all went according to protocol nothing to be suspicious of...
所有步骤都是按程序走的 没什么疑点
What were you going to say?
你刚才想说什么
Nothing
没什么
You paused. Something came to mind
有件事过了你的脑子
Captain Wu saw the telegram
吴大队长看过电文
Go on...
接着说
When I handed the telegraph to Chief Jin, Captain Wu was with him
那天我给金处长传文上去 吴大队长也在
Normally...
照理说
A classified telegram would be eyes-only for the officer in charge
这样的密电
不是业务主管是不能看的 对吧
But that day...
可是那天
When I delivered it to Chief Jin
我给金处长呈文的时候
Captain Wu didn't look away He actually glanced at it briefly
吴大队长不但没有回避 还上前看了一眼
He shouldn't have done that
照理说他不该犯这种错误
But then again... It's probably nothing
但是说穿了也没什么啊
Do you know how much blood I've shed all the years
本人追随汪主席这些年
I've served President Wang?
流了多少血汗
I was shot three times
光受枪伤就有三回
It's little weasels like you
倒是像你这样的人得了势
We should be watching out for Who knows which side you'll end up on if the tables turn?
朝秦暮楚的，谁知道你靠哪边
I see...
明白了
Until we catch the Phantom
没抓到老鬼以前
We're all still colleagues here
大家都还是同事
You rank above me - just above me-
您官又比我高一阶
And so I am showing you...
我敬您三分
...the respect you deserve
是给彼此留点余地
Let's hope you leave here safely
希望你平安走出这里
Ask whatever you want,
您尽管问
But the answer will be the same-
但我就一句话
I don't know anything
我什么都不知道
I checked
查过了
It's the number to the Gus' house
是顾家的电话
What about the list?
我是说这份清单
Anything suspicious?
有什么蹊跷
Looks normal to me
有什么蹊跷？
Don't call her family
别往她家打电话
Send someone to buy the things she's asking for
她要的东西派人买给她
What if the others start making similar requests
如果其他人也要求比照办
None of them would have the nerve
别人没这个胆
What does her family do again?
你说顾晓梦家做什么的
Her grandfather was with General Xu
爷爷在许世昌手下干过部长
Her father went into business-
到她父亲那才开始搞实业的
Textiles...
Cement, Shipping-
纺织厂 水泥厂 货运行
You name it
样样都有
They say he's close to President Wang
说是汪主席的把兄弟
Just last year, he donated a JU-52 to the Air Force
去年给咱航运队捐了一架JU-52
He donated a plane?
捐飞机？
That's what I call rich
真是有钱啊
Let's make dinner more interesting
晚饭前
Before they go down, tell everyone what the others have said
把他们对彼此的说法通通放出去
Including Gu saying she knows who the Phantom is
包括顾晓梦说她知道谁是鬼
Why aren't you eating? What's the matter?
吃啊 想什么呢
Once a bitch...Always a bitch
妖就是妖，它不是人
A mincing, conniving little bitch
修行千年它也成不了人
Councilor Jin Who are you talking about
金处长，骂谁呢
The faggot knows perfectly well
兔儿爷
Just exactly what I'm talking about
全不干人事儿
You're spoiling- My appetite
吃饭呢 吵什么呀
I'll rip your fucking head off!
嘿 我操你大爷的
Calm down, Chief
处长 处长
Let him come! The coward
别拦着 让他打啊 孬货
We'll see how hard you can get!
不信你硬得起来
Stop it!
你说什么呢
-You want some whipping? -We're all colleagues here
-我不揍死你       -都是自己人
Stop it! Calm down!
这是干什么呀 都是自己人 别
Colleagues, my ass!
自己人顶个屌用
I'm no colleague of a slanderous... rumor-spreading bitch!
造谣生非 含血喷人的都是自己人
I was merely......stating the facts
我，只是陈述事实
Facts?
事实
I'll give you facts
我让你看看什么是事实
I was shot twice last year at the battle in Yueyang
去年底打岳阳 老子身中两枪一步没退
But I still kept going Didn't back down 'till I took out the enemy pillbox
硬是拔了敌人的碉堡
Where were you then?
你在什么地方
Sipping tea and reading the newspaper in your fucking office Then whoring around after work, I bet!
上班看报纸喝茶 下班寻欢作乐
Captain Wu
吴大队长
Being a brave soldier doesn't mean you're always right
会打仗并不代表你干什么都对
Remember Deputy General Gao?
高团长怎么着
A hero in every battle he fought even lost an arm for us
少了一只胳膊 立功无数
But he still went to the other side in the end
还不是说投共就投共嘛
Say that again
你说什么
Say it again!
你再说一遍
You're calling me a traitor?
谁投共
Just giving an example
我只是举个例子
You don't need to volunteer yourself so quickly
你不用急着穿鞋
Take it easy, Captain
哎哎 老吴 吴队长
Stop it
干什么 你干什么
Get out of my way
你给我闪开点
Out of my way. This is no business of yours
你闪开点 这儿没你事
Go ahead
你动手
Let's see what kind of a hero you are
看你多英雄
If you're so strong, why don't you go pick fights with the Japanese instead of women
有力气打女人 不去和日本人较劲
Captain Wu
吴大队
May I suggest you finish your dinner first?
请您吃完再走
A man raises his hand against a woman
这一屋子的人都是死人啊
And nobody does anything?
眼看着个大男人打女人
There's no need for this
都是自己人嘛
We're all amongst ourselves
怎么弄成这样
NOBODY WILL MAKE IT OUT OF HERE ALIVE
NEED TO TAKE EXTREME MEASURES
TO HAVE ANY CHANCE OF GETTING MESSAGE OUT...
We truly apologize for the...
实在抱歉
...inconvenience to you all
这几天委屈各位长官了
Col. Takeda has specifically directed...
武田长交代下来
After the Phantom is found...
一旦揪出鬼
Each of you will be rewarded for your assistance If you'd all be kind enough
各位都会因协助办案受到奖励
To write down your ranks, pay grades...
麻烦把历年的考绩 职等
...and evaluation scores...
以及薪饷的级数写好
During the years of your service
等侦讯结束之后
You'll all be rewarded accordingly once this is over
作为论功行赏的依据
What do you want?
哎 你们干什么你们
What's going on?
怎么回事儿
Let go of me!
放开我
Let go of me! Let go!
放开我 放开我 放开我
Who'd they get?
谁啊
It's not me!
不是我
It's really not me!
真不是我
Well, then can you explain to me...
那请你解释一下
Just why your handwriting is identical to the Phantom's?
为什么你的笔迹和老鬼的笔迹这么像
Well
为什么
Someone's framing me
有人想栽赃我
It must be. It must be!
肯定是的 肯定的
Pull his pants down
扒了他的裤子
Hold your step
请留步
Commander
司令
I'm disciplining my dog
我管教我的狗
What's so funny about that?
你笑什么
There's a rat in your unit
您的单位里有奸细
What rat?
什么奸细
General Tsukeda has asked me to take full charge of this
挂尾中将已经委托我全权负责此事
Commander Zhang...
他对您的信任
I'm afraid the GeneraI's faith in you... Has been greatly shaken
因为这件事 打了很大的折扣
Do you have evidence?
有证据吗
Bring over the handwriting file
去把笔迹档拿过来
Now!
快去
If it were anyone else, this would already be over
若是别人也就罢了
But since it is Lieutenant Bai, your confidant...
偏偏是白小年 您的机要
I think it best if you prove your innocence first
您最好先自清
Commander...
司令
Commander
Help me!
救我
I'm not the Phantom!
我不是鬼
Officer Li, please get dressed immediately and come with me
请李组长穿好衣服 跟我走
Where to?
去哪儿
One minute. You have one minute to get ready
一分钟 你只有一分钟的准备时间
Please wait here.
请稍等
Please enter...
请
One of our men
Just saw Captain Wu barge into Gu's bedroom
发现吴志国闯进了顾晓梦的房间
See anything?
什么情况
It's too dark
看不到
Turn it up
把声音打开
I'm apologizing to you.
我向你道歉
I don't want your apology
请你出去
Please just leave!
我不需要你道歉
Why? Why can't we just talk it out?
为什么 我们不能把话说清楚呢
What are you doing?
你要干什么
I'll call the guards!
我叫士兵啦
I'm their commanding officer
我是他们的长官
What are they going to do to me?
他们怎么可能请得动我呢
Let go of me! Let go!
你要干什么
What's going on?
怎么回事儿
We're losing the signal...
信号不好
Your boyfriend, Liu - the actor?
你男朋友是话剧演员刘林宗
You haven't seen each other for about a week, no?
你们是不是差不多一周没有见面了
No.
是
He's with the military police now
他在宪兵队
What's he doing there?
他在宪兵队干什么
What do you think he's doing there?
宪兵队是干什么的
Commissioner!
处长好
Why didn't you stop him?
怎么不拦住他
I didn't dare, sir
我想拦没敢拦
Knock on the door
去敲门
And ask Captain Wu down to the living room
Tell him I would like to speak to him
请吴大队长到会客室 说我有事找他
Go!
Yes sir!
去，是
Commissioner, sir! No, sorry, I mean, Chief Captain, sir!
Commissioner Wang would like to...
王处长说找你有事
Talk to you in the living room
在会客室里等你
Tell him I'm sleeping
说我睡了
人体解剖学
The first time I saw you,
我第一次见你
I noticed your features
就注意到你
A narrow forehead...
前额骨窄
...high cheekbones...
颧骨突高
...and a thin nose
鼻骨细狭
Your eyes are deep-set
眼窝深大
Women with that kind of facial structure...
面部水准线较突出
这种面相的女人
...are not to be trusted
心机很深
Even if on the surface they may seem to be above reproach
但表面总做出一副不可侵犯的样子
You've been acting, all along...
你一直在演戏
What do you take Liu in for?
你们有什么证据抓刘林宗
A unit like Counterinsurgency can't allow for any uncertainty
司令部这种单位不容丝毫含糊
If you share your bed with a rebel
如果你的枕边人有问题
What else might you be sharing with him?
你也脱不了干系
Ms. Gu?
顾小姐
Ms. Gu... are you asleep?
睡了吗 顾小姐
What do you want?
有事吗
Just passing by
路过
Are you OK?
怎么了
I'm fine
我没事
I brought you a snack
给你带了点吃的
If you need anything...
有事就叫我
I'll be around
我都在
To hell with him!
他该死
If you can prove that you're not the Phantom
如果能证明你不是老鬼
It would also clear up our suspicions about Liu
也就间接证明刘林宗的清白
I suspect the resume you submitted to us...
我认为你给单位的生平资料
...was mostly made up
是假的
During the interrogation today
今天王处长的审问
Your hostility-
你态度傲慢
Only shows that you're hiding something
只是说明你心虚
You're one of our best code-breakers, I'm told
听说你是一个密码天才
But did you know that...
但是你知不知道
Every inch of the body carries a code?
我们身体的所有部位都是密码
If you can pass this examination
只要你能过这一关
You and Liu will have nothing to worry about
你和刘林宗都平安
Your physical features
人的器官
From every orifice to every limb
四肢的长短比例
All carry the genetic code of who we are...
都在传达信息
Showing our true identities
都在揭穿我们的真实身份
In order to get to that
要让你显露真面目
I'll need to break your will first
首先要摧毁你的意志
And the way to break your will
而摧毁意志的方法
Is to help you realize
就是让你发现
That your body does not belong to you
你的身体并不属于自己
It belongs to your enemy
你的身体属于敌人
Now let go
坦白吧
Give yourself over completely
把你自己完全交出来
"Wherefore, there in her shimm'ring eyes of jade...
为何在她散着金粉的眼皮之下
Shine golden pupils peering at my own?"
用那双金色的眸子 看着我
HAVE COME UP WITH A PLAN
HEAVEN HELP ME NOW
So Lieutenant Bai died during the interrogation-
所以白上尉是在审问过程中意外死亡的
Is that correct?Commander Zhang?
是这样吧 司令
Right up until he died...
...Bai insisted he was being framed
小白临死前还说，他是被陷害的
I've wronged him!
我错怪小白了
Everything we did for the Imperial Army
我替皇军做牛做马
And this is how you repay us?
你们就这样对待自己人
What else did Lieutenant Bai say?
白副官还说什么
He said the hell with handwriting
他说字迹算个屁啊
Chief Jin is a master calligrapher-
金生火是书法高手
He could imitate anyone's handwriting he wanted to
谁的字他不能仿
My condolences
辛苦了
Please take the Commander home
送司令回去休息吧
Rest well, Commander Zhang
司令慢走
We've been had
我们被算计了
The Phantom is still among us
老鬼还在这儿
We have two days left
剩下两天时间
No more mistakes
不容许任何差错
Colonel Takeda
武田君
ONE MONTH AGO
Takeda!
武田君
Any thoughts you'd like to share with us?
你有什么意见
Forgive me for being so direct
怒在下直言
But I don't believe that your plan is feasible
您的进攻计划并不可取
Nothing comes quickly or easily in battle
在战场上
The cost of a rushed attack would be staggering
急功近利的代价非常惨痛
Your opinion comes......as no surprise to me
对你的看法，我不意外
Your grandfather killed himself On the Northern front-lines
当年你爷爷在沙河前线作战，受不了压力自裁身亡
Cowardice seems to be a Takeda family tradition
“怯战”早成为你武田家的传统
We have a situation
有状况
The cripple is here!
那个老头出现了
The janitor who posts the messages at the temple?
那个贴告示的清洁工
I checked with the administration-
我跟行政处对过了
He handles the slop-water here
这里的泔水是归他管
However, he's not supposed to be here...
但他不该今天来
...until the day after tomorrow
说是过两天有事
He's swapped his shift with someone else
跟同事调了班
The Phantom's gone quiet-
老鬼不见了
They're getting worried
他们急了
The Phantom must be anxious to notify the rebels
老鬼现在最急迫的问题是
Not to carry through the assasination
怎么发出消息
Here is our chance to set a trap
取消百草堂的暗杀行动
And force the Phantom forward
我们应该引老鬼现身
Attention everyone!
跟各位报告
After three days of investigation We have made great progress
经过三天审讯 可以说是有重大斩获
We are now almost certain that
几乎可以断定
Lieutenant Bai is the Phantom
白小年就是鬼
As a gesture of appreciation for your cooperation
慰劳大伙辛苦
Col. Takeda has arranged a special lunch for today
中午武田长特别加菜
Please be punctual
请各位准时入席
Thank you
辛苦了
Hey you!
老陆
Go tidy up the dishes and bring back the plates
去把桌子收拾收拾 把骨碟换回来
I, Li Ningyu...
我 李宁玉
Graduated with honors from Wharton
堂堂美国宾夕法尼亚大学的高材生
I am not a whore
我不是妓女
I am not!
我不是
I may not share your rank...
But that doesn't mean I'm afraid of you.
我斗不过你，但我不怕你
Sis..
玉姐 玉姐
You bastard!
混蛋，把她拉回去
It's all right now
Bastard!
混蛋
Let go of me!
放开我
Come now
走
Let go of me!
These goddamned people
他妈的这帮王八蛋
We should
干脆
Just kill them all and have done with it
全部动大刑
It would make no difference to me
我倒是无所谓
But I would worry for you, Commissioner Wang
就怕你王处长今后不好办
One innocent officer has died already
已经不明不白死了一个
If we should take another life and still find no sign of the Phantom...
要是再闹出人命，却找不到鬼
What would you tell Commander Zhang?
你怎么向张司令交代
Let's go over the facts again
我们不妨再推敲一遍
I believe we can rule out Officer Li
李宁玉应该可以排除
I've looked her over carefully
我仔细地查过她
The only thing on her mind is her boyfriend
她想的都是刘林宗
Someone so weak-minded
老鬼不可能这么随性，这么脆弱
Couldn't possibly be the Phantom
What about Jin?
He looked at the old cripple when he was handing him his dirty plate
老金呢，他递盘子的时候，瞪了那老头一眼
Look at it the other way
你得反过来想
Jin has nothing to hide
If he looked at the cripple
金生火心中无鬼，有人上前收盘子，彼此眼神交汇
That only shows one thing
这只是说明
He is unguarded
When a stranger comes close, it's only natural to react
有陌生人靠近时 他自然会有所反应
If someone doesn't react...
如果不反应
They're deliberately avoiding it
反倒是刻意回避
Trying to control their focus
闪躲对方的目光
Neither Captain Wu nor Officer Gu looked at the cripple once throughout the whole meal
吴志国和顾晓梦从头到尾就没看那老头一眼
One of them is our Phantom
老鬼就在他们两人之间
Everyone come outside
所有人统统出来
Gather at the west wing immediately
到西楼集合
To prove his innocence
白副官为洗脱嫌疑
Lieutenant Bai gave his life
不惜以死明志
Right up until his death...
死前再三强调
He insisted that he was being framed
他是被奸人陷害
Lieutenant Bai was very close to the Commander
白副官和司令的关系非比寻常
But even that couldn't save him
都不免落到这个下场
I suggest you all ask yourselves
请各位扪心自问
With nothing to lean on...
你们的背景
How will you escape his fate?
有他硬
Merciful Buddha! Whoever it is, please...
阿弥陀佛 到底是谁呀
I beg you - step up!
求求你
Spare the innocent
别殃及无辜好嘛
We would rather be wrongly harsh
宁可错杀
Than wrongly lenient
不能错放
If the Phantom wants to leave, there are two ways
In a box, or in-
老鬼想要离开这里，除非死
What the-?
Motherfucker! ls there anything you won't do?
唉 唉 干嘛，还有王法吗
Calm down, Captain Wu
别急啊 吴大队
Everyone will take their turn
一个一个来
My friend...
老王
Stay away!
滚开
Stay away! Don't come close!Stay away! Stay away!
滚开 滚开
You don't want to do this, Jin
不要乱来哟 老金
I know what you do to people
我知道你的手段
It'd be worse than death
是生不如死啊
I'd rather end this here
我赏自己一个痛快吧我
Another one down
又少了一个
What do you want? What are you doing to me?
干什么 干什么
Let go of me! Let go of me!
放开我 放开我
Let go of me!
放开我
Sis! -Let go of me! -Sis!
-放开我        -玉姐
Let go of me!
放开我
Go back to your room
回房间去
Don't say a word
别说话
Go!
回去
Why aren't they making a sound?
怎么一点儿动静都没有啊
You dropped a cigarette at lunch
你中午掉了根烟
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢
There was a message on the cigarette
那根烟上有暗号
Are you out of your mind?
How many more innocent people will you let die?
疯了吧你，还想害死多少人
Officer Gu
顾晓梦
What did I ever do to you?
我什么地方得罪过你
Why are you always against me?
你老跟我过意不去
It's not about you-
我不是针对你个人
I'm just saying what I witnessed
What the fuck did YOU witness?
我只看证据，狗屁证据
The cigarette is coded
那根烟就是证据
I'm going to give it to them
我必须把它交上去
Officer Gu!
顾晓梦
No one else should have to die so you can live!
没必要为你一个人死那么多人
You bitch, I'll kill you!
我现在就杀了你
Go!
-快去        -是
Yes sir!
你也去
You too!
Yes sir!
是
The door is jammed
反锁了
Out of the way!
闪开
Let go of her!
Let go
松开
放手
You fucking whore!
臭娘们
Fuck you!
去你的
If only you'd spoken out earlier
早说不没事了
There'd have been no need for any of this
白挨这一顿
Give it here
把东西给我
During lunch yesterday...
昨天吃中午饭的时候
The chief captain took out a cigarette...
吴大队长掏烟
...and dropped it on the ground
掉了一根在地上
I could sense that something was going on
我觉得不对劲
So I covered it with my foot
所以就踩住了
Morse code?
摩斯电码
Yes
In Morse code
对
在摩斯电码里面
This represents a single word...
这些就代表一个字
"Abort"
撤
There are plenty of smokers in this building
整栋楼有几个人抽烟
But you're the only one who smokes "Three Cannons"
惟独你抽三炮台
Come on...
还想赖
I'll give you one more chance
For the sake of all our time together
念在大家同事一场，再给你一次机会
That bitch stole my cigarettes to frame me
那娘们偷我烟诬陷我
I don't know shit about codes
我哪懂摩斯码
You're all fucking blind!
She's playing you!
你他妈瞎了狗眼，是非不分
Just confess
Takeda has assured me that if you'll only confess
说吧，只要你肯说
You can be pardoned   Maybe even rewarded
武田长说了，可以戴罪立功
Our formidable Captain Wu-
吴大队长身子骨硬
Too hard for electricity
不怕电
Come- Let the Chief Captain down
来把吴大队长放下
THIS IS MY LAST CHANCE TO GET THE MESSAGE OUT
IT ALL COMES DOWN TO TODAY
Gu...
晓梦
It was a close call last night
昨天真是有惊无险
I've sewn up the rip for you
破口已经缝好了
But I'm not very good at it
可就没车边
The stitching is a bit...
...uneven...
有点不，不规整
You've been targeted...
你被锁定了
Both you and the Chief Captain
你们俩被锁定了
Captain Wu hates my guts
吴志国不甘心
He's always antagonizing me
一直反咬我
I know it isn't Captain Wu
我知道不是吴大队长
Don't worry...
放心
I'll never turn on you
我绝不会揭发你
Here, try it in
试一下衣服
When did you know?
你什么时候知道的
Just now
现在
It was a blind guess
我刚是瞎猜的
Mr. Six
六爷 您请
Ah, Chief Captain-
好久不见啊
Long time no see!
吴大队长
You're aware of Mr. Six's... pride in his work
六爷的手段你也知道
It's not too late for you to confess
你现在赶紧说还来得及
Fuck you and fuck your ancestors!
我操你祖宗
I'll come back...
下辈子
And fucking kill you in my next life!
老子剁碎了你
We're not strangers, Captain
咱们都是自己人
You were always generous to me
以前常受您照顾
So I'll be... restrained
下手会有分寸的
Now relax...
轻松啊
Breathe deeply
呼一口气
Relax, Chief Captain...
轻松啊 大队长
Tell me
说
Where is Magnum?
老枪人在哪儿
This one's good for the kidneys!
补肾水啊这瓶
So my boyfriend is one of you too?
林宗也是你们的人
You sent Liu to me?
刘林宗
You've been using me all this time-
一直都在利用我
Why me?
为什么找上我
I rank too low. Can't get enough access We hope you'd become one of us
我的业务层级太低，你才是信息的关键
This is beyond me
太可怕了
Was anything real?
你们到底什么是真的
I've always thought of you as a sister
我真的把你当姐姐
As a sister?
把我当姐姐
If they knew about this conversation
我今天要是被查获
You think I'd make it out alive?
我还有命活吗
They already got Liu
刘林宗已经被抓获了
Had you heard? Huh?
你知不知道啊
Where are you going?
你去哪儿
To turn you in
揭发你
I am going to turn you in
我去揭发你
Fantastic
To die by your hand...
非常好，我要是能死在你手上
Is probably the best I can hope for
无话可说
You're a monster!
你简直是个魔鬼
I was only doing my job
我只是在执行任务
I didn't want it to go this far either
我也不想走到这一步
Magnum... Where is Magnum?
老枪 老枪在哪儿
Right... here
就在这
You've already made it-
你已经过关啦
They think Captain Wu is the Phantom
他们现在认定是吴志国
I was the one who sent out the bad information
错误情报是我提供的
Now I need to get the word out to my comrades
我必须把消息传出去
There's only one way, turn me in
现在只有一个办法 就是你去举报我
I would never do that!
我怎么可能去举报你呢
What are you thinking?
都什么时候了
How could a message be worth more than your own life? Huh?
情报比你的命还重要吗 啊
Your life? Huh?
比命重要吗 啊
I don't care...
What other people do with their lives-
晓梦，别人怎么样我不管
But I want you to live
我要你活着
For the first time I can finally open up to you...
好不容易以真面目相对
If only for a few more days and nights to talk with you, heart to heart
我真想和你聊上几天几夜，说说心里话
But there's no time left
Do you understand? No time
可是现在没有时间了 你知道吗 没有了
I'm begging you
我求你
Turn me in
向他们举报我吧
Usually, three needles is all it takes
一般人三针下去
For an ordinary man to confess and fingerprint their testimony
认罪的认罪 画押的画押
The Chief Captain...
这吴大队长
Is indeed a remarkable man
不是凡人
Is there any other way...
还有什么别的
To make him talk?
门路
Open the gate!
Let me in!
开门
让我进去
I found this under Officer Gu's pillow-
在晓梦被子里发现的
The Chief Captain is innocent!
吴大队长是被栽赃的
Hurry up
快
Flip him over
把他翻过来
Unfettered
我本是
In the wild wastes
卧龙岗上
I mastered
散淡的人
Yin and Yang
And knew the heavens...
论阴阳如反掌
But when the country needed me, I fought
保定乾坤
先帝爷下南阳
You smoke Camels
你抽的是骆驼
And yet Officer Li found a pack of Three Cannons under your pillow
可被窝里掖的是三炮台
That's awfully damning
这可太明显了
I'm trying, really trying, to help you here
我是真的想帮助你
快
But
We're running out of time
我们没有时间了
Those aren't my cigarettes
那不是我的烟
Get her up there!
上
Stop
停
She won't talk
她什么都不肯说
How do you do, Phantom-sensei
你好 老鬼先生
We meet at last
总算见面了
How long have you been spying at the Counter-Insurgency Center.
你在单位里潜伏了多久
Do you take orders directly from Magnum?
是直属老枪指挥吗
I can guarantee you...
只要你合作
Full protection if you cooperate
我担保你的人身安全
Not only for you
不止是你
But also your family
还有你的家人
I can guarantee that
我通通可以担保
Let's not get carried away now, Takeda
武田长说大话了吧
During a strategy meeting. You assaulted a superior officer
军部高参会议你暴行犯上 重伤长官
You're about to be deported back to Japan
自己都快被贬回本土了
Where you'll probably face court-martial. You're in no position to guarantee me anything
你跟我保证什么呀
Let me put it this way
我说过
When I say I can guarantee you and your family safety
我有能力保护你和你的家人
I am also saying that
我的意思是
I am in a position
To hurt you......and your loved ones
我也有能力，伤害你和你的家人
Hello?
喂
There must have been a delay on the road
路上耽搁了
minutes later than planned
比预计时间晚了二十分钟
Number 6, South Bank-
南河沿六号
That's your parents' address, no?
是你家的地址吧
Leave my parents out of this. This has nothing to do with them
我的事儿你别扯我父母
A call for you
接个电话
Mother...
妈
在你家
Right now Another gun just like this one is pointed at your mother's head
也同样有把枪顶着你妈的脑袋
Your decision
就看你怎么处理了
Save her life and you can save your own
这不必是生死离别，只要你肯放自己一马
Enough
好了
Tell Madame Gu
告诉老太太
Her daughter will be home soon
晓梦很快就可以回去
You see
你看
That wasn't too hard, was it?
很简单
I am the Phantom
我是老鬼
I take my orders directly from Magnum
我直接受上线老枪的领导
Captain Wu never laid eyes on the telegram I made that up to frame him
吴志国确实没有看文件 是我赖他的
As for Lieutenant Bai I was the one who forged his-
Let's talk about Magnum
-还有白小年是我模仿他        -谈谈老枪吧
Where is he now?
他现在人在哪里
OK
可以啊
But not in front of him
可我不希望有人在
I have no idea where he is
我不可能知道他在哪儿
I've never seen him
我从来没见过他本人
But you must be in contact with him
那你总要跟他联系吧，否则情报如何传递
The board in front of the City Temple
还是城隍庙的布告栏
Does he post the orders himself?
What do you think?
他自己去贴的吗，你说呢
Would you do it yourself?
你会自己去吗
You're wasting my time
你说这些等于没有说
Sorry
那对不起了
But the truth is I know more about you...
我对你了解比较多
...than I do about Magnum
对老枪一无所知
Commander, sir!
司令好
Where is Takeda?
武田呢
I need to see him now
武田去哪儿了
What else can you tell me?
你还想说什么
Oh, lots...
想说的有很多啊
About your family... Your upbringing... And about that awful weak spot of yours...
你的出身 你的家庭 还有你内心的懦弱
Your grandfather became Lieutenant General after the Meiji Restoration
维新后你祖父当了陆军中将
Your father also distinguished himself
你父亲也跟着沾了光
As a Colonel in the Navy
当上了海军中佐
Indeed
你知道吗
You are a most talented spy
你的确是一个很出色的特务
Halfway through the Russo-Japanese War
日俄战争打到一半
Your grandfather killed himself in the front-line
你祖父突然在前线自杀了
No military men have ever respected you
你一直觉得同僚在用异样的眼光看你
You bitch!
你耍我
Don't shoot!
别开枪 别开枪
She was determined to die
她就是想死
And we all played right into it
我们都中计了
You never had any authority to conduct this investigation
你根本没有获得授权
General Tsukeda turned down your request-
挂尾中将当场否决了你的请求
This operation- ls entirely illegitimate!
你这次行动完全是假传圣旨
At this point, does it really matter...
...whether I was authorized or not?
我有没有得到授权，还重要吗
My goal-Is to catch Magnum
And wipe out his terrorist organization
抓到老枪，消灭反日恐怖组织，才是我这场战役的目的
I cannot return to Japan in shame
我不能以戴罪之身回国
You conducted interrogations under false military orders
你冒着假造军令的危险审问囚犯
Two ranking officers died here，Along with a Chief Captain who's half dead
If word of this gets out
这里死了两个军职人员,一个上校大队长半死不活,消息传出去,
They'll haul both of us before a court-martial
We need to find someone to pin this on
你我都难逃军法处置，必须找人顶罪
Sirs...
二位长官
I have matters to discuss with Col. Takeda
我和武田长有事要谈
Leave us be
你先下去吧
Yes sir
是
You double-crossing son of a bitch!
我操你大爷的
You son of a bitch!
Takeda!
武田长
Colonel Takeda!
我对你一直
You know I've...
I've always been loyal-
你清楚的啊
Back-stabbing bastards!
你让他
At least the Phantom wasn't able to escape
起码老鬼没有离开这儿
Stick with the original plan tonight
今晚按原定计划
Set a trap at Bai Cao Hall
在百草堂设伏
If we can catch Magnum...
抓住老枪
...we might still have a chance
是我们唯一的生路
THREE MONTHS LATER
Where did you last make port?
你们从哪里来
Taiwan?
台湾
Saigon?
西贡
No, not Saigon-
不是西贡
This ship doesn't stop there
“爱和丸号”不走那条航线
What's the point of sending more troops in?
现在增兵有何意义
This war just might end earlier than we'd thought
这场仗看来要提早结束了
I'm going home a criminal
我是罪犯
But I've got it better than you- At least I'm going home
可我有一点比你强，我要回家了
I'm here to shorten the trip
我来送你上路
"Peace at Last"
Li Ningyu!
李宁玉
There's someone here for you
After working for the puppet regime during the war
有人找你
像我这种战时在伪政府有工作经历的
You know how it is-
现在这下场
I'm really pretty lucky...
已经算好的了
...to have even this
The report you wrote helped a lot- I should thank you
这还要多谢你当时帮我写的陈情
Poor Liu, though-
我只是可怜林宗
The Japanese were going to put him in front of a firing squad
日本人原本要枪毙他的
But three days before the execution
差三天执行死刑的时候
The Japanese surrendered
日本投降了
He kept his life alright
捡回条命来
But he's never been the same
可人也废了
Anyway, you're not here to hear me complain
你来不是来听我诉苦的吧
Actually...
I'm here about the dress
我来
是想跟你借那件旗袍看看
The dress?
旗袍
The one Gu mended for you
就是晓梦亲手给你缝补的那件
Gu and l...
我和晓梦
We were both in the resistance
都是共产党地下抗日组织的
Although we were both undercover in the Counterinsurgency Center
但即使潜伏在同一个单位
She had no idea who I was
她也不知道我的身份
It wasn't until that night on the balcony
直到被关进裘庄的当晚
When I started singing "The Empty City"
我在阳台上唱起那段空城计
That she learned I was one of her comrades
她才知道我是自己人
We use the song like a secret password
这段唱腔是抗日地下组织的秘密口令
To reach out to our comrades...
Whenever we're in trouble.
凡是能够听出其中蹊跷的，就是同志
Relax, now
别老绷着脸
I lost my temper
那天我态度不好
I'm here to apologize
我来向你道歉
I don't want your apology
Please just leave!
请你出去，我不需要你道歉
-What are you doing? -Just relax
-你要干什么        -坐下
I'll call the guards!
我叫士兵啦
Stop! What are you doing?
放手啊 你要干什么
Are you trying to threaten me?
你这是人身威胁
I'm their commanding officer What are they going to do to me?
我是他们的长官，他们怎么可能请得动我呢
Let go of me!
你要干什么
-Relax now. Let's sit down and talk it out -Let go of me!
你怕什么 我们坐下来谈一谈，-放手
Relax We're both from the same village...
我们既是同事又是老乡
-l won't do anything to harm you. -Let go of me
-我怎么可能伤害你呢        -放手啊
Let go! Back off!
Just Calm down
你坐下 坐下
I know you're the one
我已清楚你的身份
But I beg you
Comrade to comrade. Hide yourself
现在情况危急 作为同志我建议你
Let me take the heat
这个情况由我来顶
Try to get the word out
你设法传递信息
But it was me that sent out the false intelligence
错误消息是我发出去的
I should take the consequences
应该由我负责
You couldn't stand the torture
你顶不住的
You're in no position to tell me what to do- I only take orders from Magnum
我只受老枪指挥，无可奉命
Then why was Gu always clashing with you?
那晓梦当时为什么先咬你啊
It's one of our tricks
这是一种默契
If two comrades are taken in at the same time
如果两个人同时被捕
We fight, accuse each other, do whatever it takes...
为了确保不被一网打尽
To keep them from getting everyone
就必须站在对立面
That way, at least one of us would get out alive
起码保一个人出去
Let go of me!
放开我
If word doesn't get out tonight the resistance will be crushed
You must survive. Find a way to get the message out
I am MAGNUM. I hereby order you to turn me in
You stay alive. I have a plan
You dropped a cigarette at lunch
你中午掉了根烟
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢
There was a message on the cigarette
那根烟上有暗号
Are you out of your mind?
疯了吧你
I didn't understand at the time what she was trying to do
我当时并没有明白
She'd decided from the start that she'd sacrifice herself
晓梦其实早就决定牺牲自己
To make sure I got the message out
好让我把讯息传出去
That song, "The Empty City"
我那首空城计
With a few changes in the tune and lyrics
随着曲调唱词的变化
It becomes a tool for transmitting urgent messages
它还可以传递情报
BAD INFORMATION
ABORT MISSION MAGNUM
When Gu made you turn her in
晓梦让你举报她
It was to make sure that I got out
就是要保我出去
What if you'd been unconscious when you got to the hospital?
可要是你在医院昏迷不醒
Or nobody was there to hear your message?
或者没有接应的人
Then it would all have been for nothing
晓梦不是白白牺牲了吗
In fact...Gu had also sewn a mission abort message...
晓梦实际上把取消行动的情报
...onto her undergarments-
同时缝在了自己的内衣上
As another way to get the word out
作为另一种途径
BAD INFORMATION ABORT MISSION PHANTOM
Nobody was going to get out of that mansion alive
因为只有死人才能离开裘庄
So Gu...
晓梦
Used her body to pass on the message in death
也用自己的身体把情报传了出去
She also wanted me to pass on
晓梦让我转告
The message she left for you
她给你的话
It's in the lining of your dress
都留在这旗袍里面了
You'd know this better than me-
这个你比我懂
It's all Morse Code
全是摩斯码
THIS IS MY LAST CHANCE TO GET THE MESSAGE OUT
IT ALL COMES DOWN TO TODAY
I'M NOT AFRAID OF DYING-
BUT ONLY FEAR MY LOVED ONES WON'T KNOW WHAT I'VE DIED FOR
I AM LEAVING THESE WORDS IN THE HOPE THAT
Ll AND MY FAMILY WILL FORGIVE MY DECISION
I am leaving these words in the hope that...
我身在炼狱留下这份记录
Li and my family will forgive my decision
是希望家人和玉姐原谅我此刻的决定
But I have faith...
但我坚信
That you will come to understand my intentions
你们终会明白我的心情
My dearest loved ones...
我亲爱的人
Though my death brings you great pain
我对你们如此无情
But our people face mortal peril
只因为民族已到存亡之际
I would do anything to stop it
我辈只能奋不顾身
Even if it's giving up my little life
挽救于万一
Whatever they may do to my body
我的肉体即将陨灭
My soul will always live on with you
灵魂却将与你们同在
What the enemy can never understand is...
敌人不会了解
That Phantom and Magnum represent not individuals...
老鬼 老枪 不是个人
They represent a brotherhood
而是一种精神
And a faith in justice
一种信仰
Honorary presented by Hualu Cultural Enterprises Co., ltd.
Issued by Hualu Electronic Audio & Video Publish Co., ltd.
cym合并中英字